Joshua Ludwig

213 Bainbridge St, Philadelphia, PA

484-429-1584 jhludwig94@gmail.com joshludwig.com

OBJECTIVE

Analytical decision-maker with 2 years experience driving growth in a gritty early-stage start-up, seeking an opportunity where my adaptable thinking and determination will create value for both my organization and its users/clients. I want for my new role to strengthen my already strong foundations in digital analytics, and project management in an enthusiastic and motivated workplace.

EDUCATION/CERTIFICATIONS

University of Delaware

Bachelor of Science in Management Information Systems

May 2017

HIPPA

• HIPPA Security and HIPPA Privacy for Business, valid through 2021.

Google Analytics

- Google Analytics Academy, Google Analytics for Power Users, valid through September 2022.
- Google Analytics Individual Qualification, valid through September 2020.

RELEVANT COURSEWORK

Statistics With R, Introduction to Probability and Data (Through Duke University) MISY 430/431: Applied Project Management

- Developed a form submission web app for the Department of Hospitality at the University of Delaware to log student service hours using agile methodology, improving data reporting/retention processes.
- Informed client with project management tools (Wireframes, Gantt Chart, Process Flows, User Stories, ERD Design).

WORK EXPERIENCE

VeryApt

Operations Manager

January 2018-Current

- Created listing contracts with large residential rental companies (roughly \$50,00 in annual revenues) and performed account management/retention on that clientele.
- Led and managed link building strategy (Broken link replacement, infographic/social media post creation, blogger outreach).
- Monitored and reported on traffic source performance to management.
- Acted as the procuring agent in 100+ residential leases, maintaining a conversion rate above the targeted 10% of users that enter our system (roughly \$100,000 in annual revenues).
- Lead generation through partnership building (personalized program housing guides).
- Mastery of Industry standard business technologies (Microsoft Outlook, Google Analytics, Google Data Studio, Microsoft Project, Microsoft PowerPoint, Microsoft Excel, Trello, Slack, Adobe Spark, GitHub).
- Reported to shareholders and executive management on traffic, profitability, growth, etc.
- Created hand-off documentation to solidify business processes that previously lacked recording.

Hardwick Benfer LLC

Data Analyst

August 2017-December 2017

- Took source data (10,000+ records) provided by a Fortune 100 company in legal discovery and modeled using Excel (macros, vlookups with multiple criteria, pivot tables) to enhance prosecution.
- Presented Data Studio visualizations to defense teams resulting in multiple pre-trial settlements.

John I. Weinberg Center for Corporate Governance

Corporate Governance Intern & Teaching Assistant, Professor Charles Elson

February 2015-May 2017

- Teaching Assistant for "Advanced Seminar in Corporate Governance" where I consulted students on term papers, designed and led review sessions, and graded examinations/papers.
- Planned and executed bi-annual Governance Symposium (budgeting, logistics, venue reservation).

ACTIVITIES

Philabundance

Volunteer

January 2019-Current

 Accumulated 50 volunteer hours packing and organizing Hunger Relief Center boxes, with an estimated individual impact value of \$500 since starting.